[Music]
hi I'm Nick welcome back to Polar Ice
Creamery there's been a bit of a gap
from the last video so apologies about
that but everyone voted for a s'mores
ice cream in a pole I put up on YouTube
and that's what we've done here
we made a s'mores video actually I'll
put a picture up of the tub because it's
right at the back there and I can't get
at the moment of Ben and Jerry's gimme
small and that was incredible really
really good it had
a really nice kind of warm flavor but I
think personally I could have done with
a little bit more of that burnt
marshmallowy taste to it and when
everyone voted for this I was really
quite excited to make it again we're
gonna do it a completely different way
so if you want to see how we attack this
look at that tub then stick around
and we'll show you
so to start this ice cream base we're
going to put our milk in the pan and
we're going to use a proprietary
stabilizer mix in some of the sugar here
which you can see me mix in once that's
really nicely combined essentially what
you're trying to do is just remove any
lumps of stabilizer so that it all
dissolves nicely in your liquid
once that's mixed add your sugars into
your milk and then we're going to add in
some malt extract here this is a new
ingredient for me we don't get this many
places in England so I'm really excited
to actually finally get hold of it it's
actually used in the making of beers
ales and lagers which is where I got
this from anyway we're going to add that
into our milk make sure we're warming it
up nicely and that completely dissolves
before we add in our milk powder and
then as you know my milk powder is
rubbish it's going to take us ages to
get that dissolved and homogenized
once it's ready we're going to take it
off the heat and put our mixture in a
container where we're going to add in
our cream and then finally our vanilla
extract this is homemade vanilla extract
it's triple fold so really really strong
stuff then you're going to pop that in
the fridge overnight to chill down
the next stage for this one is our
graham cracker crust now we don't get
graham crackers here in UK the best
thing we've got as an alternative is
digestive biscuits so you're going to
take your biscuit of choice put it in a
blender and get it really nicely fine
down to a really fine powder and then to
that you're gonna take your butter melt
it in a microwave and then bring it back
mix it all together and then pack out a
baking sheet lined with parchment pop
that in the oven and then when that's
ready take it out let that cool down
completely before you put it in the
fridge
the next stage of this is making your
marshmallow fluff so what we've got here
is a Banbury we've got an inch worth of
water just simmering underneath as you
can see and we've got our egg whites in
the bowl to that we are going to add our
table sugar and our golden syrup you can
use corn syrup if that's what you have
available I'd avoid the high fructose
corn syrup though as there just really
is no need to have that in your pantry
these days once that comes up to 75
degrees Centigrade you're going to take
it off the pan and you're going to put
it on a worktop pop a dishcloth or towel
or something underneath the bowl so it
doesn't slide around and get in there
with your whisk or hand mixer or
whatever kind of mixer you have
available what you're trying to do here
is cool the mixture down whilst
incorporating the air as the mixture
cools down it will thicken up and leave
you with a really really lovely glossy
smooth marshmallow fluff once I it's
ready you can add in your vanilla
extract give it one final little whisk
and then pop that aside until you're
ready to use it it will keep up for
approximately 48 Hours covered
if you're gonna put it in the fridge
just keep an eye because after a few
days this can start to separate
depending on the ingredients you use
and the final element to this s'mores
ice cream is the chocolate pieces so
we've taken a little mold here this is
actually Coffee Bean shaped I really
like this mold I might use it again you
want to take your chocolate we've used a
milk chocolate here and melt it in the
microwave to that you're going to add in
a small amount of deodorized coconut oil
so deodorized coconut oil is just
coconut oil that has been passed through
a filter to remove the actual Taste of
coconut and what you're left with is
just the fat adding it to your chocolate
will
make it Harden slightly less and make it
easier to work with in your mold so once
you've combined your coconut oil with
your chocolate
Stir It really well to make sure it's
all nicely combined and then fill up
your mold as you can see here once it's
ready pop it in the fridge until later
[Music]
after your ice cream base is completely
chilled in the fridge take it out put it
in your ice cream machine to churn a lot
of people ask if I pre-chill my ice
cream machine this one I do I recommend
you do with any ice cream machine to be
fair depending on the ice cream machine
you use will depend how long it's
recommended to chill it so for mine I
just put it on 10 minutes let it chill
right the way down and it will speed up
your churning process
whilst your ice cream is churning you're
going to want to prepare your chocolate
and your biscuit so take your chocolate
pieces out the mold and put them in a
little bowl and take your graham cracker
crust that you've made and chop it up
into little cubes whatever size you
fancy I've gone for about one centimeter
cubes here put that in a little bowl
because we're gonna add them into the
ice cream in a minute
once your ice cream churn is at the
final stages and you can see the little
ribbons forming on the top you can add
in your small chocolate pieces and your
graham cracker crust keep that going
until it's ready and then we're going to
load up the tub and look at this tub
it's incredible and then we're going to
layer in our marshmallow fluff on top of
the ice cream with the chocolate pieces
and the graham cracker crust oh my word
my mouth is watering quick get it in the
freezer before we dish this up and
demolish it
so there's been a gap between the making
of this ice cream and the dishing up
part of this ice cream it's been weeks
so I'm quite excited to try this let's
get some scooped up tint well let's get
some scooped up into the bowl and see
what it tastes like
foreign
[Music]
first things first when putting that
marshmallow in and dishing up torching
it really I mean look at it
it just you can smell it you can smell
that burnt marshmallow and that's really
what you wanted torching it it might
seem a bit strange for putting a flame
or fire or blowtorch into your type of
ice cream it doesn't it doesn't melt the
ice cream because you're literally just
touching that surface
but that was really what was missing
from the original Ben and Jerry's give
me small flavor so let's dig in and see
what this tastes like
[Music]
wow
that is
good
really good
should you get that
you get that burnt caramelization to the
marshmallow fluff
he can add super buttery biscuit pieces
throughout you get those nice little
chocolate chunks I think I probably
next time I'd add a little bit more
coconut oil to the chocolate just so
it's a little bit more
ganache rather than hot I actually quite
like hard chocolate pieces but some
people might
so if you want slightly softer pieces of
chocolate in this then just add a little
bit more coconut oil and that will
actually make it softer when it freezes
but The Malt flavor for this vanilla
base that's essentially what what it is
it's a vanilla based with malt
extracting oh it's super warming when it
goes down it tastes like a a mugaholics
it's familiar it's autumnal heading into
winter it makes you think of fires and
sitting there in front of them yeah it's
really really good and that blend of all
those ingredients I'm going to take a
picture so you can actually
see what I'm looking at here
it's a Perfect Blend
of all these kind of ingredients and I'm
really glad that I tried this version
for the marshmallow fluff normally I use
a Swiss meringue for marshmallow inside
ice cream because it's a much more
stable kind of process because you're
adding in
an acid so cream of tartar or Tata as
some people like to call it you're
adding in that which is an acid which
stabilizes the egg whites
and here you're you're adding the invert
sugar so here I used the golden syrup
you could use any invert sugar you like
it doesn't really make any difference
um but it's really sticky it's really
really sticky and
and that is exactly what you
oh it smells incredible
well I literally could eat the whole tub
of that
you know what this is this is so much
better than that benadry's gimme small
if you liked that one oh
let's have some more
[Music]
if you liked
the original Ben and Jerry's give me
some more or you like s'mores you like
that warming kind of familiar
caramelization flavors
do this one make this one you will not
be disappointed I promise you so
again sorry for the delay we're getting
back on track now so
with next week we're gonna do the
stabilizer video which you've all voted
for and asked for which is quite an
interesting one bit more of a sciency
one for those that need it and want it
and on the build up to Christmas we've
got a lot of nice warming things we're
gonna make we're going to look at eggnog
again we're not going to make an eggnog
ice cream we're just going to make
eggnog and drink it drink it because you
know that's the fun bit so as always
thanks very much for liking and
subscribing this video we're nearly a
thousand subscribers which is great
I hope you all have a good day and we'll
see you next time
[Music]